psrk.com 2011-10-19

# PropertyShark - Privacy Policy

**PropertyShark.com Privacy Policy**

This policy describes the types of information PropertyShark.com gathers from its users of the PropertyShark.com network of Web sites and how that information is used. Please read this policy carefully before you provide us with any personal information. If you have questions about this policy, please email us at [support@propertyshark.com](mailto:support@propertyshark.com). 

**Information We Collect**

We log your IP address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Web site and track usage statistics. Your IP address may vary each time you visit, or it may be the same, depending on whether you access our site through an always-on type of Internet connection (e.g., cable modem or DSL), or through a dial-up connection (e.g., AOL or Earthlink). Either way, it would be extremely difficult for us to identify you through your IP address, and we make no attempt to do so. If you reached our site by clicking on a link or advertisement on another site, then we also log that information. This helps us maximize our Internet exposure, and understand our users' interests. All of this information is collected and used only in the aggregate; that is, it is entered into our database, where we can use it to generate overall reports on our visitors, but not individual reports that identify you personally. 

We also place a small text file known as a "cookie" on your computer's hard drive. A cookie may contain information that allows us to track your path through our Web site and to determine whether you have visited us before. However, unless you register with us, it contains no personally identifiable information that would allow us to identify you. Cookies cannot be used to read data off of your hard drive, and cannot retrieve information from any other cookies created by other Web sites. We use cookies in this manner to help us understand how visitors use our site, and to help us to improve our site. You may refuse to accept a cookie from us by following the procedures specific to your Web browser. Although you may do so, you may find that your browser reacts strangely when visiting not only our Web site, but other Web sites as well. Since cookies don't provide us with any information from which we can identify you, we suggest you allow us to place one on your computer. 

We may use Web beacons on our site or other sites and may permit third parties to place them on our site to monitor the effectiveness of advertising or for other legitimate purposes. A Web beacon, also known as a "Web bug," is a small, graphic image on a Web page, Web-based document or in an e-mail message that is designed to allow the site owner or a third party to monitor who is visiting a site. Web beacons are often invisible to the user because they are typically very small (only 1-by-1 pixel) and the same color as the background of the Web page, document or e-mail message. Web beacons are represented as HTML IMG tags in the Web page; users can click on "view profiles" of the Web page to see whether the page is using a Web beacon. Web beacons collect the IP address of the computer that the Web beacon is sent to, the URL of the page the Web beacon comes from and the time it was viewed. Web beacons can also be linked to personal information. For example, advertising networks use Web bugs to add information to a personal profile of what sites a person is visiting and to determine what banner ads to display based on the profile. Another use of Web bugs is to provide an independent accounting of how many people have visited a particular Web site. Web bugs are also used to gather statistics about Web browser usage at different places on the Internet. 

We record a list of the property reports which you may have viewed recently as well as a history of any subscriptions or communications you may have had with our customer service personnel, including any problems with the service you may have reported.

We also give you the option to give us your email address and other personal information so we can send you relevant emails on behalf of PropertyShark.com, our affiliates or third parties. 

**How We Use the Information We Collect**

We use the information we collect to: 

  * Contact you for customer service reasons
  * Send you emails which you have requested to receive
  * Send you certain marketing communications relating to the PropertyShark.com service
  * Diagnose and fix site problems

You may opt-out by contacting us at our customer service line or by sending an email to [privacy@propertyshark.com](mailto:support@propertyshark.com). We may also use the information you provide to allow us to contact you for administrative purposes; for example, to tell you about changes to our privacy policy.

**Disclosure of Information**

PropertyShark.com does not rent or sell personal information about you to other people or non-affiliated companies, except when we have your consent to do so, as necessary to complete a transaction you have requested, when required by law, or when permitted to protect our rights or property. We reserve the right to use in any manner and disclose any non-personal information that we collect including cookie and traffic data. 

We may release personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to enforce or apply our policies; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our rights or property, or to protect our user from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, our site or services; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay. 

We may use third party service providers to assist us with the administration of the site or otherwise perform services on our behalf, including transaction processing and sending email. Such third parties may be supplied with or have access to your personal information solely to provide services to us or on our behalf. 

Information about our users and the site is a business asset of PropertyShark.com. Therefore, information about our users, including personal information, will be disclosed as part of any merger or acquisition, creation of a separate business to provide the site, our services or fulfill products, sale or pledge of company assets as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the company. 

**Security**

We use commercially reasonable security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. However, we cannot guarantee the protection of information against interception, misappropriation, misuse, or alteration or that your information may be not be disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. You should be aware that we have no control over the security of other sites on the Internet you might visit, interact with, or from which you buy products or services. 

**Your responsibilities**

You will receive a password and account designation upon completing the registration process. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of the password and account and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account. You agree to (a) immediately notify PropertyShark.com of any unauthorized use of your password or account or any other breach of security, and (b) ensure that you exit from your account at the end of each session. PropertyShark.com cannot and will not be liable for any loss or damage arising from your failure to comply with these instructions.

**Personal information collected from government agencies**

We recognize that publishing public information about real property necessarily involves the publication of information about people. The information provided on this site is protected by the Freedom of Information Act, the corollary state laws, and the First Amendment; however, we oppose the use of the information on this site to invade the privacy of anyone.

As a courtesy, we permit limited suppression of personal information for homeowners with regard to their primary residence; owners of commercial and investment property such as multi-family apartment buildings, office or retail buildings are not included in this policy. If you wish to have your personal information removed from this website, contact us. You will need to provide documented proof that you are the person in question and that you live at the property in question, and we will take steps to remove references to your information on the site. As our site is updated regularly, we cannot promise than any such changes will be permanent.

Phone number data is the responsibility of your telephone service provider or the public agency which provided it. If you wish to have your phone number removed from the site, contact your provider or the appropriate agency to have your phone number de-listed or removed. It may take three to six months for this change to appear on the site.

**Policy Changes**

We reserve the right to change this policy should we deem it advisable to do so. If we make significant changes that affect the use or disclosure of your personal information, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the changes and to give you the opportunity to cancel your registration.
